Guide to the Autographs of English Literati
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
"Autographs of English literati"
1800-1820
OSBORN D98
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
0.1
(1 volume)
MSS. Collection of autograph letters of various English literary figures.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
For provenance information, consult the appropriate curator.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
The following finding aid is a complete inventory of the contents of Osborn d98. This list was reformatted from previously existing cataloging.
Autographs -- Great Britain
- Osborn d98
  - ADAMS, JOSEPH, 1756-1818
    - AL to Robert Wilkes, [1809] (Box 1)
      Scope and Contents
      Berners Street
      1 p.; 18 x 11 cm.
      Discusses proofs which he would like
      to see.
      d.98/229
  - BELL, JOHN, 1745-1831
    - ALS to Mr. Jeffrey, 1818 Nov 19 (Box 1)
      [London]
      1 p.; 19 x 11 cm.
      Asks for permission to use the
      "Annual Register" of Robert Dodsley
      (1702-1764) for the year 1761.
      d.98/79
  - BELOE, WILLIAM, 1756-1817
    - AL to Mr. Jeffrey, [c. 1865] Apr 13 (Box 1)
      British Museum
      1 p.; 18 x 12 cm.
      d.98/169
  - BOOKER, LUKE, 1762-1835
    - ALS to Lackington and Co., 1800 Mar 1 (Box 1)
      Dudley
      3 p.; 19 x 12 cm.
      Inquires as to selling a portion of
      his collection of books.
      d.98/67
  - BRAY, WILLIAM, 1736-1832
    - AL to William Upcott (1779-1845), 1816 Jul 31 (Box 1)
      Gt. Russell St.
      1 p.; 19 x 13 cm.
      Invitation to dinner.
      d.98/241
  - BRITTON, JOHN, 1771-1857
    - LS to Mr. Jeffrey, 1818 Mar 25 (Box 1)
      10 Tavistock Place
      1 p.; 11 x 13 cm.
      Inquires about prints of topography
      and antiquities.
      d.98/77
  - BRITTON, JOHN, 1771-1857
    - LS to William Upcott (1779-1845), 1816 Nov 15 (Box 1)
      Tavistock Place
      1 p.; 19 x 12 cm.
      Sends on a pamphlet and inquires
      about prints.
      d.98/191
  - BURNEY, CHARLES PARR, 1785-1864
    - ALS to Samuel Sotheby (1771-1842), 1816 Jun 10 (Box 1)
      Greenwich
      List of items he wishes to purchase.
      d.98/165
  - BUTTERWORTH, JOSEPH, 1770-1826
    - ALS to [Robert Wilkes], 1806 Apr 17 (Box 1)
      Fleet Street
      Asks him to use the services of a
      Mrs. Vickers for printers parchment
      as "it will be a real charity to an
      honest deserving Widow with 4
      children."
      d.98/249
  - CAULFIELD, JAMES, 1764-1826
    - ALS to an unnamed recipient, 1812 May 23 (Box 1)
      n.p.
      1 p.; 20 x 13 cm.
      Concerns the bankruptcy of a Mr.
      Stace.
      d.98/195
  - COLQUHOUN, PATRICK, 1745-1820
    - AL to Mr. Appleby, 1817 Oct 28 (Box 1)
      1 p.; 15 x 11 cm.
      Requests certain stamps and that
      some books be sent to a client of
      his in the East Indies.
      d.98/237
  - DANIELL, THOMAS, 1749-1840
    - AL to Mr. Jeffrey, 1809 Mar 2 (Box 1)
      Howland Street
      Presents the recipient with "the
      whole of the "Oriental Scenery""
      published in 1808.
      d.98/1
  - DANIELL, WILLIAM, 1769-1837
    - AL to Geoffrey O'Brien Wyndham, 3rd earl of Egremont (1751-1837), [no yr] Apr 5 (Box 1)
      9 Cleveland Street
      1 p.; 20 x 12 cm.
      Sends the first volume of the
      "voyage round Great Britain."
      d.98/5
  - DEMPSTER, GEORGE, 1732-1818
    - LS to Thomas Cadell (1742-1802), 1770 Jul 23 (Box 1)
      Abergavenny
      1 p.; 11 x 16 cm.
      Sends a bill. d.98/209
  - DIBDIN, THOMAS FROGNALL, 1776-1847
    - AL to Mr. Griffith, 1827 Dec 12 (Box 1)
      Kensington
      Sends the recipient's brother to his
      publisher for copies of his books.
      d.98/11
  - EDWARDS, JAMES, 1757-1816
    - ALS to Robert Wilkes, n.d. (Box 1)
      1 p.; 13 x 20 cm.
      Sends a corrected copy of a
      manuscript.
      d.98/227
  - ENGLEFIELD, SIR HENRY CHARLES, BART., 1752-1822
    - ALS to Mr. Griffith, 1803 Mar 28 (Box 1)
      Barnes Terrace
      Order for port and sherry.
      d.98/179
  - EVANS, JOHN, 1767-1827
    - ALS to J.T. Deacon, 1819 Sep 6 (Box 1)
      Islington 2 p.; 19 x 12 cm. Discusses the recipients work to be taken by the author of the letter. d.98/223
  - FREELING, SIR GEORGE HENRY, 1789-1841
    - ALS to Robert Harding Evans (1778-1857), [ca. 1812] (Box 1)
      Gen. Post Office
      Inquires as to whether he has
      received any mail.
      d.98/55
  - GOOD, JOHN MASON, 1764-1827
    - ALS to Robert Wilkes, [no yr] Sep 16 (Box 1)
      [London] 1 p.; 17 x 10 cm. Discusses the publishability of a work. d.98/85
  - HALES, WILLIAM, 1747-1831
    - ALS to Robert Wilkes, 1818 Jan 29 (Box 1)
      Killesandra
      2 p.; 19 x 12 cm.
      Requests material.
      d.98/135
  - HIGHMORE, ANTHONY, 1758-1829
    - 2 ALS to Robert Wilkes, 1809 (Box 1)
      1809 Aug 16 and Sep 8 Ely Place and Dulwich. 5 p.; 20 x 12 cm. Both letters discuss the publication of a work concerning public charityand about which the author consulted
      Sir Richard Phillips (1767-1840).
      d.98/251, 255
  - HUNT, STEPHEN HENRY LEIGH
    - ALS to Mr. Stride, 1824 Nov 3 (Box 1)
      Tavistock St.
      2 p.; 18 x 11 cm.
      Instructs the recipient to place the
      matter concerning "Sir Gerard" into
      an attorney's hands.
      d.98/155
  - JOHNSON, JOHN, 1777-1848
    - ALS to Mr. Godson, 1820 Jun 7 (Box 1)
      Lee Priory
      1 p.; 10 x 13 cm.
      Requests fifty copies of a book on
      behalf of the authoress who is not named.
      d.98/215
  - KNOX, VICESIMUS, 1752-1821
    - ALS to Robert Wilkes, 1807 Nov 26 (Box 1)
      Tunbridge
      1 p.; 11 x 15 cm.
      Concerns revisions to his text.
      d.98/245
  - LEAKE, WILLIAM
    - ALS to Mr. Perry, n.d. (Box 1)
      Devonshire Street [London]
      1 p.; 21 x 13 cm.
      Requests that the enclosed statement,
      now missing, be included in the
      paper.
      d.98/159
  - MACARTHUR, JOHN, 1755-1840
    - ALS to Mr. Lambert, 1819 Sep 3 (Box 1)
      Recommendation for a "pressman."
      d.98/115
  - MACDONALD, JOHN, 1759-1831
    - ALS to Mr. Gosden, 1819 Nov 22 (Box 1)
      Exeter
      Returns a misprinted copy of his
      work.
      d.98/25
  - MASERES, FRANCIS, 1731-1824
    - ALS to Thomas Bensley, 1807 May 26 (Box 1)
      Inner Temple
      1 p.; 16 x 13 cm.
      Requests that all copies of his
      "Historia Anglicana Selecta
      Monumenta" be sent to Mr. Robert
      Wilkes, printer.
      d.98/183
  - MASERES, FRANCIS, 1731-1824
    - ALS to Robert Wilkes, 1805 Aug 8 (Box 1)
      Sends more copy for the 6th volume
      of the "Scriptores Logarithmici".
      d.98/71
  - MUELLER, WILLIAM, D. 1846
    - AL to Robert Wilkes, 1810 May 15 (Box 1)
      41 Haymarket
      Inquires whether Wilkes will
      undertake a printing.
      d.98/17
  - NARES, ROBERT, 1753-1829
    - ALS to an unnamed recipient, 1804 Nov 12 (Box 1)
      Prefers to have a copy of "Johnson's
      Letters" (Samuel Johnson, 1709-1784)
      in calf rather than in sheepskin.
      d.98/221
  - PARK, THOMAS
    - ALS to Mr. Smeeton, [1816] Sep 9 (Box 1)
      Hampstead
      1 p.; 14 x 12 cm.
      Returns an corrected version of a
      manuscript to be printed.
      d.98/197
  - PLATT, SIR THOMAS JOSHUA, 1790?-1862
    - ALS to James Perry (1756-1821), n.d. (Box 1)
      London
      Explains that Perry will not be sent
      for by the court until necessary and
      that when he is asked he should
      bring the manuscript in question.
      d.98/113
  - RADCLYFFE, WILLIAM
    - ALS to Mr. Bayley, 1810 Oct 15 (Box 1)
      College of Arms
      Replies to an earlier correspondence
      and sends the recipient elsewhere
      for proper reply to his question.
      d.98/217
  - ROBERTSON, ROBERT, 1742-1829
    - AL to Robert Wilkes, 1804 Jun 25 (Box 1)
      [Greenwich]
      Sends corrections.
      d.98/259
  - ROGERS, SAMUEL, 1763-1855
    - ALS to an unnamed recipient, n.d. (Box 1)
      St. James's Place
      1 p.; 11 x 9 cm.
      Requests a woodcut.
      d.98/235
  - RYMER, JAMES
    - ALS to [Robert Wilkes], 1810 Sep 17 (Box 1)
      Reigate
      Sends proofs and corrections.
      d.98/33
  - ST. LEONARDS, EDWARD BURTENSHAW SUGDEN, BARON, 1781-1875
    - LS to R. Wilkes, 1805 Jan 1 (Box 1)
      Lincolns Inn
      1 p.; 18 x 13 cm.
      Apologizes for the delay he may have
      caused; accompanied by a slip noting
      approval of a draft.
      d.98/139
  - SHIELD, WILLIAM, 1748-1829
    - ALS to James Caulfield, n.d. (Box 1)
      1 p.; 15 x 9 cm.
      Sent with his corrections.
      d.98/61
  - STEWART, JOHN, 1749-1822
    - ALS to [?Mr. Gosden], [no yr] Apr 30 (Box 1)
      Cockspur St.
      1 p.; 7 x 18 cm.
      Instructions not to bind his books
      as he may have more material.
      d.98/133
  - THOMPSON, BENJAMIN, 1776?-1816
    - AL to Mr. Gosden, n.d. (Box 1)
      1 p.; 16 x 11 cm.
      Requests that books be sent to Aaron
      Arrowsmith (1750-1823).
      d.98/101
  - TOWNSHEND, GEORGE, 1788-1857
    - ALS to William Frederick Deacon (1799-1845), [1819 Sep 1] (Box 1)
      Sandhurst
      2 p.; 19 x 11 cm.
      Requests another copy of his
      "Prospectus."
      d.98/45
  - UPCOTT, WILLIAM, 1779-1845
    - ALS to William Dean, 1821 Jan 5 (Box 1)
      London Institution
      3 p.; 21 x 13 cm.
      Concerns the value of a Virgil
      printed at Venice.
      d.98/211
  - UPCOTT, WILLIAM, 1779-1845
    - ALS to Mr. Gosden, 181? Jan 21 (Box 1)
      1 p.; 10 x 20 cm. Order for 3 sets of "Topography."
      d.98/43
  - VALPY, ABRAHAM JOHN, 1787-1854
    - ALS to [?Lackington, Allen and Co.], 1817 (Box 1)
      1 p.; 6 x 12 cm.
      Order for catalogues.
      d.98/41
  - VALPY, J.
    - ALS to Robert Wilkes, 1803 (Box 1)
      Reading
      Inquires about a lost sheet of
      corrections.
      d.98/73
  - VALPY, RICHARD, 1754-1836
    - AL to Lackington, Allen and Co., 1800 Apr 24 (Box 1)
      [Reading]
      Places an additional order.
      d.98/37
  - WARTON, JOSEPH, 1722-1800
    - Memorandum: autograph MS endorsed by Isaac Reed (1742-1807), 1780 Jan 10 (Box 1)
      2 p.; 21 x 13 cm. On Alexander Pope (1688-1744) and given to Reed. d.98/239
  - WILKINSON, ROBERT
    - ALS to James Caulfield, 1822 Jan 31 (Box 1)
      Requests that corrections to his MS
      be made as soon as possible.
      d.98/59